M.Amin Tehrani

Date of birth: 12/09/1998

Gender: Male

CONTACT



Via Venezia, 22, 30039 Stra, VE, Italy (Home)



t.mohammadamin@gmail.com



(+39) 3891586723



github.com/mohammadT77



linkedin.com/in/amin-tehrani77



+393891586723 (Whatsapp)

ABOUT ME

Having experienced several years as a software engineer, I'm currently pursuing a Master's in Computer Engineering with a focus on Artificial Intelligence. I aim to enhance my skills, stay up-to-date with the latest developments, and achieve my career goals through a combination of work and study.

WORK EXPERIENCE

01/02/2021 - 01/02/2023 Tehran, Iran

Python/Django Lead teacher and Tech expert Maktab Sharif

(part-time, approximately 10 hours/month) As a 6-month boot camps Teacher:

- teaching Python basics, intermediate, advanced
- · teaching Django basics to advanced
- · teaching flask basics
- teaching RDBMSs (PostgreSQL)
- designing, assessing projects, and showing best practices as well
- teaching git vcs
- Teaching web development relevant knowledge and skills (network, html/ css/js)

As Lead teacher and Tech expert (For):

- refining and prescribing boot-camps syllabus
- holding extra practice sessions for all web boot-camps students
- · organizing interviews with candidate mentors and teachers
- · observing and evaluating fresh mentors and teachers

Address Tehran, Iran | Website https://maktabsharif.ir/

01/08/2021 - 01/09/2022 Tehran, Iran

Software architect and Team lead IranSign

Analyzing, designing, and implementing a mobile-embed live server for PKI to perform encryption, signing, and verifying on various channels including Bluetooth, USB, etc.

- extracting user stories from business requirements
- interpreting user stories into technical descriptions
- designing an MVC-based arch for a server inside a mobile phone
- providing UMLs (Class, Sequence, Use-case)
- implementing a real-time, socket-based server in the mobile application
- implementing abstract classes as the blueprints for other teammates
- writing unit tests (TDD)
- · assigning tasks to my team members
- · holding periodic meeting sessions
- R&D on interfaces given by different mobile OS and frameworks (IOS, android, flutter)
- implementing on the Android studio platform (Java/Kotlin) as the pilot.

Address Tehran, Iran | Website iran-sign.com/en

01/04/2020 - 01/02/2021 Tehran, Iran

Django developer Dantia

(full-time, one of the three co-founders)

Dantia was the first Iranian startup to serve Al-based analytics for the Iran Capital Market.

- · analyzing the business requirements with other mates
- · defining visions and milestones
- implementing core service using Django
- writing RESTful APIs using Django Rest Framework
- crawling the core website of the Iran exchange market
- · fetching data from external APIs
- preprocessing and normalizing data before passing it to the AI engine
- documenting source codes for later uses
- establishing co-work environments (git, task managers)

(Dantia failed due to the market depression in Feb 2021)

Address Tehran, Iran

01/07/2019 - 01/04/2020 Tehran, Iran

Full-stack developer Barg Niki Resan

(contract)

- Interpret business requirements into software descriptions
- designing ERD and implementing database
- Implement services APIs on php Codelgniter
- deploying and maintaining source code on servers
- · designing the mobile-first UI
- implementing the client app on Android Studio (java) integrating APIs
- testing and debugging the project
- · documenting APIs for other developers' future uses

Address Tehran, Iran | Website https://bargniki.com

01/10/2018 - 01/05/2019 Tehran, Iran

Full-stack developer Bazmand (Tehran Municipality)

(contract, one of the three co-founders)

Bazmand was a waste-management platform (ordered by the municipality of Tehran, Iran), piloted in 3 districts there with more than 10k users.

- interpreting software requirements, having extracted business demands
- implementing the monolithic server using PHP Codelgniter
- implementing RESTful APIs for all user roles
- designing general theme
- designing UI for 5 distinct Android applications for each role
- implementing all the applications
- deploying server source code on the dedicated server
- testing, debugging, and maintaining after the launch

(quit in July 2019, yet the brand is still officially in my possession.)

Address Tehran, Iran Website https://cafebazaar.ir/app/com.cyropolis.bazmand.citizen?l=en

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

01/09/2022 - CURRENT Padova, Italy

Master's degree University of Padova

Address Via 8 Febbraio, 2, Padova, Italy | Website https://www.unipd.it/en/ | Field of study Computer Engineering - Artificial Intelligence

01/09/2016 - 01/09/2021 Tehran, Iran

Bachelor's degree Kharazmi University

Address Tehran, Iran | Website https://khu.ac.ir/en | Field of study Computer Engineering | Final grade 16.05 / 20

LANGUAGE SKILLS

MOTHER TONGUE(S): Persian

Other language(s):

English

Listening	Reading	Spoken production	Spoken interaction	Writing
C1	C1	B2	B2	B2

DIGITAL SKILLS

Python | Django | DRF | Linux | Flask | PHP | Socket programming | Git | Scrum | Software architecture | Software Refactoring | Design Patterns | SOLID design

SOF1

Complex Problem solving | Advanced planning and prioritizing | Advanced Communication and Team-working | Lead ership | Decision-making